<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Philosophy on Marlow&#39;s Listener</title>
    <link>/categories/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Philosophy on Marlow&#39;s Listener</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Queen Context</title>
      <link>/2020/06/30/queen-context/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/30/queen-context/</guid>
      <description>Is the glass half-full or half-empty?
Both, of course. Why ask?
If drinking the cup of hemlock then it’s still half-empty. If partying down, then it’s half-empty already. If taking a pre-exam purgative, it’s only half empty.
If pouring champers, and much of the glass is bubbles, it’s only half-full. If only a mile from the oasis, it is still half-full.
Queen Context: How to allocate attention between what’s there and what’s not is how a pragmatic analyst lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The eternal &#34;who&#34;</title>
      <link>/2020/06/22/the-eternal-who/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/22/the-eternal-who/</guid>
      <description>We perceive the light reflected from ten million leaves and see the pattern trees. We perceive the air on our skin or the dinner in our gut and feel the pattern me. But me should be us, an ecosystem of bacteria and viruses to which we each are the primordial forest. Nor is industrial agriculture missing – we suppress or enhance fertility, apply pesticides and fertilizers and sprinkle fairy dust into our brains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thou Should Nots</title>
      <link>/2020/06/22/thou-should-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/22/thou-should-not/</guid>
      <description>   Don’t listen to the voice that says go for it! Don’t ignore the voice that says you’ll be sorry Don’t focus on your failures, you can always find new ways of screwing up Don’t expect it to be different this time Don’t worry about tomorrow, you’ll know it when it comes  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>