<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quotation on Marlow&#39;s Listener</title>
    <link>/categories/quotation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Quotation on Marlow&#39;s Listener</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/quotation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Deus ex machina</title>
      <link>/2020/06/22/deus-ex-machina/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/22/deus-ex-machina/</guid>
      <description>Fabula rasa
 A reconciliation between the two conflicting requirements is effected by a resort to make-believe.
 Thorstein Veblen, Theory of the Leisure Class</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generation gap</title>
      <link>/2020/06/22/generation-gap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/22/generation-gap/</guid>
      <description>Truth must change her fashion
 It is not too much to say that no formula which expresses clearly the thought of one generation, can convey the same meaning to the generation which follows.
 Brooke Foss Westcott, D.D., D.C.L Bishop of Durham, Late Regius Professor of Divinity, Cambridge, and Canon of Westminster</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magna Carta</title>
      <link>/2020/06/22/magna-carta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/22/magna-carta/</guid>
      <description>Considered in its immediate historical context, Magna Carta is at least as much of a property lease amendment as a constitution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nice customs curtsy to great kinds</title>
      <link>/2020/06/22/nice-customs-curtsy-to-great-kinds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/22/nice-customs-curtsy-to-great-kinds/</guid>
      <description>… all canons of reputability and decency, and all standards of consumption, are traced back by insensible gradations to the usages and habits of thought of the highest social and pecuniary class—the wealthy leisure class.
 Thorstein Veblen, Theory of the Leisure Class</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Noblesse obligee </title>
      <link>/2020/06/22/noblesse-obligee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/22/noblesse-obligee/</guid>
      <description>It is only in the middle classes, Stephen, that people get into a state of dumb helpless horror when they find that there are wicked people in the world. In our class, we have to decide what is to be done with wicked people; and nothing should disturb our self possession.
 Lady Britomart, Major Barbara by G.B. Shaw</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Grand Pooh-bahs were ever thus</title>
      <link>/2020/06/22/the-grand-pooh-bahs-were-ever-thus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/22/the-grand-pooh-bahs-were-ever-thus/</guid>
      <description>The potentates of this world are sufficiently apt to consider themselves as possessed of an inherent superiority which gives them a right to govern and makes mankind their own; and this infatuation is almost every where fostered in them by the creeping sycophants about them and the language of flattery which they are continually hearing.
 A Discourse on the Love of our Country by Richard Price, delivered on Nov.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>